Elihu Thomson Papers 1865-1944 Mss.Ms.Coll.74
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Subject files, 1866-1944; 7 boxes; 3.25 linear feet
  - Optical Society of America, 1924, 1932
  - [Organ blueprints], ca. 1902
  - Oscillograph, n.d.
  - Oxford Club. Application for membership, 1892
  - Pan-American Exposition, 1901
  - Panama Canal. As to the construction of the, n.d.
  - Panama Canal. Map showing line of proposed lock canal with summit elevation at 85 feet
  - Papers written. [Lists of published], 1869-1934
  - Papers written. [List of unpublished, autobiographical], n.d.
  - Patent. Means for utilizing solar heat, 20 Oct. 1897
  - [Patent agreement between Elihu Thomson and C.B. Cushing], 18 Sep. 1882
  - Patent Centennial, 1891
  - [Patent relating to a new method of converting heat into mechanical energy], Feb. 1892
  - The Patent Review. Description of electric meter in, 1891
  - Patents. Major Thomson, n.d.
  - Patents desirable to have. List of, n.d.
  - Patents of Elihu Thomson. United States, n.d.
  - Patents of Elihu Thomson relating to electrical switching devices, 5 May 1936
  - Peabody Academy of Science, n.d.
  - [Philadelphia. Locations of first Thomson-Houston shops in], 21 Apr. 1933
  - Philadelphia Astronomical Bulletin, Jan. 1924
  - Philadelphia Electrical Exhibition, 1898
  - [Photographing planets, stars], n.d.
  - [Photographs. List of?], n.d.
  - [Physical Society. Minutes], n.d.
  - The Physical Society of London. Report on series in line spectra, 1922
  - Plantacion Rubio temperature record, Oct.-Nov. 1901
  - Power of attorney, 1892
  - Power of attorney from Munro Lee Ross to Henry Esson Irvine, 17 Jun. 1884
  - [Power of attorney re: patent for dynamo electric machines], 12 Jul. 1906
  - Press releases. General Electric Co., 1935-1940, n.d.
  - Priestman oil engine--Advertisement, 1892
  - Primer of electricity No.0, n.d.
  - Prism for lenses and lens combination. To find radius from angle of, [ca. 1910?]
  - Public Welfare Medal, n.d.
  - Radio, television, and talking picture patents, 19 Jan. 1932
  - Radiology. Literary contributions of Elihu Thomson to the science of, n.d.
  - Recapitulation. Electric lighting statistics and electric railways, 1891
  - Regulators for electric lamps. Specifications and patent improvements on, 1879
    -See also Ser.I, Houston, Edwin J. and Elihu Thomson to the Hon. Com[missioner] of Pat[ents], 26 Jul. 1879
  - Research laboratory [report]. Advisory Council of the, 1905
  - Restof Mining Co., 1916, 1918
  - Reviews of Beloved Scientist, 1944, n.d.
  - Rice, Edwin Wilbur, Jr. Agreement with, 27 May 1889
  - Robinson, John. [Memorial], 1925
  - Roentgen Society of the U.S. Application for membership, n.d.
  - Rotor, n.d.
  - [Royal Electric Co. Sale of], 1 Jun. 1887
  - Royal Institution of Great Britain, Jan. 1899
  - Ruhmkorff Coil Core. Construction data of 16-inch
  - Schèma de la désintégration [radiation], 1917
  - Science League of America, n.d.
  - Scientific American Cyclopedia of Receipts--Advertisement, 1892
  - Screen for projection. Invention [of], 22 Sep. 1925
  - Sedgwick, William T. Vote of Corporation, n.d.
  - Self-compunding dynamo. Readings taken from tests made with Prof. Thomson's, 1895
  - Smithsonian Institution. List of models for, 10 Jan. 1898
  - Société d'Encouragement pour l'Industrie Nationale, 1905
    in French
  - Specifications for commutators for dynamo electric machines, ca. 1881
  - Spectrum for the glass of [?]. The intervals between the lines in the, [ca. 1907?]
  - [Steel plate coated by Coleman & Tile Coppering Co.], 25 Apr. 1902
  - [Stockholders meetings. Misc. companies'], 1891
  - Submarine periscopes. Specifications for, 1917
  - Sullivant Medal, Joseph, 1922-1923
  - Sullivant Medal, Joseph. Report of the Committee on award of the, Sep. 1922
  - Synthetic methanol, n.d.
  - Tablet in honor of the late Elihu Thomson, 1940
  - Telegraphing without wires, n.d.
  - [Television], 7 Aug. 1928
  - Testimonial in honor of Elihu Thomson, 27 Sep. 1930
  - Thomson & Houston Electric Light Co. of Canada. Agreement, 1883 (Box Series III-8)
  - Thomson & Houston Electric Light Co. of Canada. Assignment to American Electric Illuminating Co. for Thomson improvements for electric currents, 7 Jan. 1884
  - Thomson & Houston Electric Light Co. of Canada. Sale and transfer to American Electric and Illuminating Co., 7 Jan. 1884
  - Thomson & Houston Electric Light Co. of Canada. Sale and transfer to American Electric and Illuminating Co. for Thomson & Houston regulator for electric lamps, 7 Jan. 1884
  - Thomson & Houston Electric Light Co. of Canada. Sale of patents to, 14 Apr. 1883
  - Thomson & Houston Electric Light Co. of Canada to American Electric and Illuminating Co. of Maine. Schedule A to sale and transfer, 7 Jul. 1884
  - Thomson Electric Welding Co., Apr. 1916
  - Thomson Electric Welding Co. Agreement, 24 Apr. 1888
  - Thomson-Houston Electric and the Thomson Electric Welding Companies. Annual banquet of the foremen, electricians, and assistants of the, 30 Jan. 1892
  - Thomson-Houston Electric Co. Agreement
    - Folders #1-2, 20 Apr. 1887
    - Folder #3, 20 Aug. 1891
  - [Thomson-Houston Electric Co. Agreement re: electric welding], 20 Jul. 1887
  - Thomson-Houston Electric Co. Agreements, 20 Apr. 1880
  - [Thomson-Houston Electric Co. Formation of], 9 Jan. 1906
  - Thomson-Houston Electric Co. Statement of profits and surplus account and local companies using the arc system, 1 Feb. 1889
  - Thomson-Houston Electric Co. Stockholders' reports, 1886-1916
  - Thomson-Houston Electric Co. vs. the Lorain Steel Company--Document filed with the U.S. Circuit Court, 15 Jan. 1900
  - Thomson-Houston International Electric Co. Agreement, 18 Aug. 1891
  - [Thomson-Houston inventions. Importance of], 5 Oct. 1933
  - Thomson-Houston plants
    - Folder #1, 1883-1886
    - Folder #2, 1883-1888
  - Thomson-Houston regulator for electric lamps. Sale and transfer of, 5 Mar. 1883
  - Thomson Quarter Century Club
  - Thomson Scholarship Fund. Voluntary subscriptions for
  - Thomson Scientific Club. Constitution and by-laws of the, 20 May 1889
  - Thomson Scientific Club. Meeting announcements, 1891-1892
  - Thomson Spot Welder Co. vs. Ford Motor Co., n.d.
  - Thomson Welding Association to Thomson Electric Welding Co. Bill of Sale from, 24 Apr. 1888
  - [Thomson Welding (electric) patents. Sale to Westinghouse of the], 1887
  - Turbine Council. Minutes, 28 Mar. 1905
  - United States Bureau of Standards. Legal weights (in pounds) per bushel of various commodities, 1905
  - United States Bureau of Standards., 1906
    - Verification of standards of mass
  - United States Electrical Commission, n.d.
  - [United States Electric Light Co.], 21 Apr. 1933
  - United States Electric Lighting Co. and their associates. Agreements between Houston and Thomson and the, 1881
  - United States House of Representatives. A bill to fix the standard of weights and measures..., 3 Dec. 1901
  - University of Pennsylvania. Moore School of Electrical Engineering, 1924
  - Voltaic batteries. Agreement between Thomson, Houston and Thomas McCollin re: revivifying, 13 Feb. 1879
  - Von Schulz & Low. Analysis of "crude T.A.", 8 Nov. 1915
  - Von Schulz & Low. Mineral analyses report, 28 Oct. 1915
  - "Walking Beam" meter, n.d.
  - Weekly Digest [of electrical patents], ca. 1893
  - Welding patents. Agreement, 7 Jun. 1887
  - Welding patents [foreign]. Agreement, 7 Jun. 1887
  - [Welding times], 20 Mar. 1901
  - West Lynn Odd Fellows' Building Association, 1891
  - Western Association of Electrical Inspectors., 1925
    - Resolution on Elihu Thomson
  - Will [of Elihu Thomson], 22 Jan. 1936
  - World's Columbian Exposition, 1892
  - X-ray apparatus. Patents of Elihu Thomson relating to, n.d.
  - X-ray apparatus without interrupter..., n.d.
  - X-rays of Röntgen, 26 Feb. 1896
    -See also Ser.XI, X-ray of Röntgen, for photograph
- Series IV. Published Works, 1869-1932; 3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet
  Autograph and typescript drafts, notes, comments, and printers' page proofs. Printed articles, journals, reprints, and photostats have been moved to the Thomson Reprint Collection. Title pages or first pages of this printed material were photocopied onto acid-free Permalife bond paper and included in the manuscript files before the printed material was transferred to the reprint collection. The only printed materials not removed from Series IV are several ephemeral pieces which are extremely fragile due to age.
  Manuscripts of Thomson publications are arranged alphabetically by title, and focus on his lifelong interests in electrical systems, welding, astronomy, optics, etc. Many facets of Thomson's professional career and inventions are documented throughout the series. The manuscripts date from Thomson's first published article, "The Triumphs of Science" in his high school paper (1869), to the works published towards the end of his career. Besides manuscripts of papers prepared for publication in scientific journals, this series also contains manuscript drafts of Thomson's many editorial pieces published in both newspapers and journals throughout the country.
  Comments by Thomson appear on separate sheets and on the actual manuscripts and evaluate the historical importance of many publications. It appears he was making these notes to a future editor of his biography/bibliography.
  - Alcohol and the future of the power problem, Aug. 1906 (Box Series IV-1)
  - Arguments against annual patent renewal fees, Oct. 1919
  - The big achievements of Dr. Steinmetz, Nov. 1923
  - Cathodographic experiments, Feb. 1896
  - The centrifugal creamer from laboratory and farm, May 1921
  - [Coffin, Charles Albert]. He invented methods of business, Jul. 1926
  - The coming of the solar eclipse, Aug. 1932
  - Compounding dynamos by armature reaction, Jul. 1895
  - Concerning lightning rods, Jun. 1891
  - Concerning recent auroras, May 13 and 14, 1921, Jun. 1921
  - Cross, Charles Robert, May 1928
  - A curious action of attraction by alternating currents, Mar. 1893
  - Curious effects of Hertzian waves, Jul. 1894
  - Development of arc lighting, Sep. 1922
  - Dielectric strength of oils under alternating potentials, Feb. 1896
  - Dynamic induction at high potentials and frequencies, Mar. 1892
  - The earliest dynamo, Sep. 1928
  - An early dynamo Grant, George, Feb. 1920
  - Early experimental work in the development of alternating-current motors, Oct. 1930
  - The early years of the Thomson-Houston Electric Co., Dec. 1921
  - The electric annealing of armor plate, Mar. 1895
  - The electric arc and lighting by arcs, Dec. 1911
  - Electric wave and phase indicator for alternating and undulatory currents, Jan. 1888
  - Electric welding
    - Folder #1, Dec. 1886
    - Folder #2, 1926
  - Electric welding development, Jun. 1904
  - Electric welding, from lecture room to industry, 1924
  - Electrical advance in the past ten years, Jan. 1898
  - Electrical phenomena; the alleged etheric force--test experiments as to its identity with induced electricity (with E.J. Houston), Apr.-May 1876
  - Electricity during the Nineteenth Century, Feb. 1901
  - Electricity in 1876 and in 1893, Jan. 1894
  - Electricity since Franklin's time, Mar. 1924
  - The epoch-making discoveries of the years 1819-1820, Dec. 1920
  - Evolution in street lighting, Aug. 1921
  - Experiments on the electric discharge in vacuum tubes, Jun. 1891
  - Experiments with Ruhmkorff coil and spark, Jan.[?] 1876
  - The fall of a meteorite, 1912
  - Faraday and Edison, Mar. 1932
  - The Faraday Centenary, Sep. 1931
  - The first electrical apparatus built and used by Franklin, Sep. 1920
  - The first extant communication presented to the academy, May 1912
    Amer. Acad. of Arts and Sciences
  - From an eminent scientist, Mar. 1919
  - Further experiments with condenser spark and air gel, Feb. 1892
  - Fused silica in the electrical industry, Feb. 1924
  - Helium, Mar. 1927
  - Helium in deep diving, Jan. 1927
  - High potential transmission, Mar. 1892
  - Historical sketch of the Thomson-Houston Company, Apr. 1924
  - How shall the trolley be applied on steam roads?, Feb. 1895
  - Induction by high potential discharges, Feb. 1892
  - The life of incandescent lamps, Feb. 1893
  - The light of the firefly, Oct. 1910
  - Lightning: its risks and how to avoid them (with C.A. Adams, Louis Bell, D.C. Jackson, and A.E. Kennelly), Mar. 1916
  - Loss by hysteresis, Apr. 1890
  - The magneto-optical effect and a correction, Oct. 1927
  - Making a 10-inch telescope objective, Jul. 1931
  - The manufacture of permanent magnets, Apr. 1895
  - The mechanics of optical polishing, Oct. 1922
  - The microphone relay (with E.J. Houston), Jul. 1878
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1926 (Box Series IV-2)
  - New Haven Journal Courier. [Editorial], 16 Aug. 1929
  - The "new" three wire system of H. Ward Leonard, Jun. 1872
  - Note on the recalescence of iron, Apr. 1889
  - A novel luminous phenomenon effect of field of some kind on light beams, 31 Mar. 1921
  - A novel magneto-optical effect, Jun. 1921
    -See also Ser.X, Magneto-optical effect
  - A novel magneto-optical effect (further observations), Jul. 1921
  - On aviation's future uses, Aug. 1912
  - On recalescence in steel, and its relation to expansion, magnetization, and hardening, May 1889
  - On the change in color produced in certain chemical compounds by heat (with E.J. Houston), Aug. 1871
  - On the inhalation of nitrous oxide, nitrogen and other gases and gaseous mixtures, 15 Nov. 1873
  - On the transmission of power by means of electricity (with E.J. Houston), Jan.-Feb. 1879
  - On welding by electricity, 1890
  - Physiological effects of alternating currents of high frequency, Mar. 1891
  - Pioneer investigations on dynamo machines fifty years ago, Jun. 1928
  - Possibilities of liquid air in electrical work, Jul. 1897
  - A possible means of cutting down the mosquito population, Jan. 1932
  - Prof. Elihu Thomson on American electrical engineers, 2 Nov. 1889
  - Prof. Elihu Thomson's new alternating machine, Sep. 1890
  - Progress in electricity, 1897
  - Quartz mirror to time light, Nov. 1924
  - Recent developments in the electrical arts, Aug. 1912
  - Recent progress in the art of electric welding, Mar. 1926
  - Rendering visible a magnetic field, Sep. 1928
  - [Reply to Mr. George Hill's comments on Prof. Thomson's discussion of S.D. Greene's paper, "Electricity on board ship"], Feb. 1899
  - A retrospect, May 1908
  - A review of the development of direct-current motor design, Mar. 1928
  - Roentgen ray burns, Apr. 1897
  - Roentgen ray diffusion phenomena, Jun. 1897
  - The Roentgen ray source, Apr. 1896
  - Roentgen rays act strongly on the tissues, Nov. 1896
  - Safety devices with transformers, Mar. 1888
  - A short story in wireless, Jul. 1922
  - Silica glass or fused quartz, Feb. 1923
    -For photographs, see also Ser.X, Silica glass or fused quartz
  - Single phase alternating motors, Mar. 1893
  - Some considerations as to the nature of comets and their probable relation to the sun, May 1910
  - Some highlights of electrical history, May 1934
  - The spectroscope, Mar. 1914
  - A speculation regarding the cause of Roentgen rays, Jun. 1897
  - Storage batteries, Mar. 1894
  - A suggestion or hypothesis concerning zodiacal light, Oct. 1927
  - ["Tackling Tech." Foreward to], Jul. 1922
  - The term "subdivision of the electric light", Sep. 1922
  - That cat again!, May 1895
  - Thomson discovered electric waves fifty years ago, Jul. 1922
  - The trend of invention and improvement in the electrical field, Aug. 1907
  - A tribute to Dr. Monroe B. Snyder, 1932
  - The triumphs of science, Oct. 1869
  - A unique patent statute, Mar. 1895
  - Unlock vast stores of energy, Aug. 1923
  - An unusual meteoric fall, Oct. 1908
  - Vision and the measurement of light and illumination, Nov. 1912
  - Whose "new three wire system" is it?, Jul. 1892
  - Why the 200-inch telescope?, 6 Dec. 1929
  - William Thomson, Lord Kelvin, Dec. 1916
  - Wireless considerations, Oct. 1922
  - Wireless telegraphy, Oct. 1908
  - Work, Harold K., on "Electroplating on aluminum and its alloys." Comments on the paper of, 14 Apr. 1928
  - Work in the first decade of roentgenology, Sep. 1932
- Series V. Unpublished Works, 1866-1937; 2 boxes; 1 linear foot
  School papers, autobiographical essays, poetry, short papers on ideas and inventions, and any works which were not identified as published. These manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by title and date from Thomson's high school years to the end of his life.
  Among the many high school papers preserved in this series, probably of most interest is the "Universal Journal." Produced by the Junior Scientific and Literary Society of Central High School in Philadelphia, this journal is primarily written in Thomson's longhand. Other manuscripts of interest in this series include the many short, anecdotal papers written by Thomson about his childhood in Philadelphia and the origins of his studies in the sciences. While most of these papers are autograph manuscripts, some appear to have been dictated to and typed by Thomson's second wife, Clarissa Hovey Thomson. A great deal of these autobiographical papers must have been used by David O. Woodbury in the biography, Elihu Thomson, Beloved Scientist (1944), as the stories are repeated throughout this book.
  - The alchemist, [ca. 1866-70] (Box Series V-1)
  - Alternating current, n.d.
  - [Astronomical telescope], n.d.
  - Attitude as to religious beliefs, Jun. 1926
  - [Autobiographical notes. Miscellaneous], n.d.
  - [Autobiographical notes dictated by Elihu Thomson to Clarissa Thomson], Jul. 1933
  - [Autobiographical sketch] for John Fritz, n.d.
  - Automatic spark advance, 4 Oct. 1904
  - A balloon trip, n.d.
  - Be silent, and pass for a philosopher, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Benevolence, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Books, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Breman winding machine
  - Bridge, n.d.
    [poetry]
  - Central High School, Apr. 1929
  - The chemical nature of steam, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Chemistry (B.4), [ca. 1866-70]
  - Chemistry (C.6), [ca. 1866-70]
  - Comments on "Prof. Elihu Thomson's new method of regulating currents or potential in the secondaries of transformers", 26 Apr. 1889
  - Comments on proposed specifications of lightning rod, Committee of the National Fire Protection Association, 21 Apr. 1904
  - Concerning aeroplanes in war, n.d.
  - Continuation of activity during stay out of school, 16 Nov. 1926
  - Crocker, Francis B. Electric lighting, [May 1901?]
    book review by E.T.
  - The development of electric station power plant, n.d.
  - Dynamo work and its development, 1929
  - Early days in Philadelphia [and] Philadelphia days, Jul.-Aug. 1926
  - Early wireless experiments, 1929
  - Early work in wireless, Mar. 1935
  - [Early years], n.d.
  - The earth, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Edison. Memo relating to the work of Mr. Thomas A., May 1915
  - ...Edison's work during many years, May 1928
  - Electric arc. Notes on the [enclosed?], n.d.
  - Electric welding, n.d.
  - An electrical detonator, n.d.
  - Electrical measurements, 4 Dec. 1912
  - Electricity eighty years ago, n.d.
  - "Electroplating on aluminum and its alloys." Comments on the paper by H. Work, Apr. 1928
  - Eloquence, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Experience is the school where man learned wisdom, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Faraday's diary, Dec. 1932
  - First impressions of the seas, 1926
  - First visit to the Adirondacks in 1872, Oct. 1925
  - Fleming, J.A.
    - On Prof. Elihu Thomson's electromagnetic induction experiments, 14 May 1890
      comments on
  - Foreward as to electrical welding, Jan. 1922
  - Forms of radiation in a Crookes tube, n.d.
  - Further remarks on the use of fuse oil, Mar. 1928
  - Fused quartz, 30 Jan. 1924
  - Fused silica as a material for specula, n.d.
  - Fuse oil as a remedial agent in respiratory disorder, Sep. 1926
  - General features of the Thomson-Houston system of arc lighting, 1883
  - [Greek and Latin], Jun. 1931
  - High frequency electric induction, 1893
  - ["History of radio telegraphy and telephony" by G.G. Blake. Remarks by Elihu Thomson on]
  - Hodges-Podges, n.d.
    poetry
  - The horseless carriage, ca. 1900
  - [Houston, E. Additional notes on], 8 Mar. 1935
  - A humorous incident at the World's Fair in Chicago, 1893, ca. 1925-26
  - Impressions, n.d.
  - In regard to the running of a greenhouse, Nov. 1919
  - Induction coils and condensors
  - Industrial research twenty-five years ago, Aug. 1923
  - Intellect, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Interest in astronomy, Nov. 1925
  - Interest in natural phenomena, 1929
  - Interest in optical work, Nov. 1925
  - Keely reminiscences, ca. 1893-94
  - Life, n.d.
  - The life of James Watt, n.d.
  - Lighting, 24 May 1921
  - Limits of potential, n.d.
  - Luminous indicator for push button or similar signals, 7 Aug. 1928
  - Dr. MacLaurin's service as President of [M.I.T.], [Jun. 1920?] (Box Series V-2)
  - The manufacturers of Philadelphia, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Marconi's trans-Atlantic trials, 21 Jul. 1926
  - Matter and mind, [ca. 1866-70]
  - [Maxwell wave transmissions], n.d.
  - Medicine. Comments on, n.d.
  - Memorandum as to telephony, 1929
  - Memory, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Meteor crater. Remarks on, 1 May 1911
  - [Meters], n.d.
  - The microscope, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Moon, n.d.
  - More about wireless, Oct. 1922
  - The mountain top, n.d.
  - My darling, "J'aime te", n.d.
  - The natural forces, [ca. 1866-70]
  - The nature of comets and their probable relation to the sun
  - Nature's electricity, n.d.
  - Necessity is the mother of invention, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Night, [ca. 1866-70]
  - The Northern Lights, n.d.
  - Note of April 1st concerning continuation of investigation of novel luminous phenomenon, Jun. 1921
  - Note on a peculiar sunset occurring on April 7, 1929, Apr. 1929
  - Notes on shadow bands observed...with M.B. Snyder, May 1900
  - Notes on the moon, Nov. 1921
  - Our canary, n.d.
  - Our moon in eclipse, Jun. 1929
  - Owed to A. Rohrer, Jul. 1890
  - The period of the Civil War, Sep. 1927
  - Philadelphia A and B, ca. 1925-26
  - The photographic art, [ca. 1866-70]
  - A physical consideration of meteor flight, Aug. 1916
  - Poetry, [ca. 1866-70]
  - [Poetry. Miscellaneous], 1937; n.d.
  - [Progress and invention in electrical work?]
  - The progress of chemical science, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Progress in electricity, [1905?]
  - Quartz window, 28 Feb. 1927
  - Reason, [ca. 1866-70]
  - Recollections of Central High School days, n.d.
  - Reflection on the airborne seeds of the dandelion, Sep. 1926
  - Regenerating stove, 28 Oct. 1919
  - Regenerative house, Nov. 1919
  - Repulsion apparatus and rotary induction apparatus
  - [Science], n.d.
  - Science (energy), [ca. 1866-70]
  - Scientific microcosm. Report of reviewer, Jan. 1870
  - Sketch of the life of Captain Stuart Thomson of U.S. Army Ordance Dept., n.d.
  - [Snow], [ca. 1930]
  - The so-called "flying machine dinner", Jul. 1926
  - The solar eclipse of Jan. 24, 1925, [ca. 1925-26]
  - Sparker outfit, 3 Oct. 1904
  - Specification of electric lamps and safety devices
  - Steam, [ca. 1866-70]
  - The story of electric welding, 1929
  - A suggestion as to the nature of the streaks around lunar craters, Dec. 1901
  - [Thomson-Houston arc lighting system], n.d.
  - Travel, [ca. 1866-70]
  - A tribute to Dr. Thomas Corivin Mendenhall, 1924
  - Unknown, 1891
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.1, 19 Jun. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.2, 3 Jul. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.3, Sep. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.4, 16 Oct. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.5, 30 Oct. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.6, 13 Nov. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.7, 27 Nov. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.8, 11 Dec. 1868
  - The Universal Journal, v.1, no.9, 18 Dec. 1868